mmaglobal.com 2006-06-15

# MMA Global - Privacy Statement

| About  
---  
Mission Statement  
Board of Directors  
Initiatives & Policy  
MMA Worldwide Chapters  
About the MMA  
Join the MMA  
Info & Resources  
Industry Overview  
Mobile Marketing Ecosystem  
Articles  
Statistics/Resources  
Glossary  
Case Studies  
Industry Links  
Awards  
Member Job Postings  
MMA Initiatives & Policy  
Working Groups  
Code of Conduct  
Best Practices  
Standards  
Meetings & Events  
Event Calendar  
Speaking Opportunities  
Sponsorship Opportunities  
News Room  
Press Releases +  
MMA In The News  
Newsletters +  
Logos  
Case Studies  
Case Studies +  
  
**Privacy**

Most established ad sellers and marketers recognize this growing concern, and the realization that their brands will suffer if consumers believe their privacy is being violated. In the wireless space, consumers are even more sensitive since devices are more personal and travel with the consumer. 

The failure to respond effectively to privacy issues and risks can result in adverse consequences that range from outright market rejection to regulatory enforcement action, to loss of data flow, or to costly litigation. The MMA, in furtherance of its mission to promote Mobile Advertising and Commerce has taken a proactive stance in establishing the MMA Privacy Guidelines for member organizations that set minimum acceptable standards for protecting the privacy of online users. These standards will serve as guidelines by which MMA member organizations can establish individual privacy policies while ensuring the privacy of users is uniformly protected. 

In addition to establishing guidelines for wireless marketers, the MMA follows a strict policy for any information submitted on the MMA website, addressed below. 

**Information Collection and Usage**  
The MMA only collects personal information from site visitors on a voluntary basis. This information may include: 

  * first and last name 
  * title 
  * company name 
  * company address 
  * phone and/or fax number 
  * e-mail address 
  * credit card information (e.g., type, #, expiration) 

The personal information that MMA collects is used by the MMA to process orders that have been placed by individuals through registrations or product inquiries. All personal information collected via the MMA Website will only be used for its intended purpose. If there is a change in use of such information, notification will be explicitly stated within the contents of the Website. All marketing efforts undertaken by the MMA are targeted to a business audience (i.e., not consumers nor children). The MMA complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. This requirement will be posted wherever the MMA collects data within the MMA site, including registration. The MMA does not collect highly sensitive data (e.g., medical or personal financial information), other than credit card number as listed above, which is used to process orders or registrations.

Individuals must affirmatively request to join and remain on our e-mail lists by contacting MMA staff at [](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com)[mma@mmaglobal.com](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com). The MMA does not compile, buy, sell, rent or trade consumer mailing lists. Other information volunteered by the customer via site registration, for example, may be used for future marketing and educational efforts (e.g., relevant industry events, MMA co-sponsored events, educational programs, relevant industry information, MMA specific products) to that individual. 

**User Access**  
The MMA is committed to providing reasonable and practical access to allow visitors to identify inaccuracies in their personal information. Each user has the right of access to personal data they have submitted through the MMA Website. Visitors may submit inquires about the accuracy of personally identifiable information they have previously submitted through the MMA Website; visitors may also request to have information removed. When practical, the MMA will, upon request, modify or delete personally identifying information. 

If you would like to add your name, check and/or correct your information, or remove your name from the MMA mailing list, e-mail us at [](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com)[mma@mmaglobal.com](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com) or write to us at the address below. 

**Third Party Distribution**  
Personal information provided to the MMA generally will not be disseminated to third parties. However, event registration information (e.g., first and last name, title, email address, company name and address) may be provided to event sponsors for a one-time use only. If you do not wish to receive communication from a third-party sponsor of a MMA event or other program, please inform the MMA by e-mail at [](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com)[mma@mmaglobal.com](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com), calling or writing to the MMA at the address below. Personal information collected by the MMA is stored in our database for a reasonable time period with which information remains current, and is updated periodically. The MMA may divulge information as necessary to comply with state and federal laws (e.g., subpoenas, search warrants, etc). 

**Use of Cookies and Log Files**  
The MMA reserves the right to analyze its Web site logs in an effort to improve the value of its site (e.g., improve the content and support services on the MMA site, and to update our records). However, the log files are not personally identifiable and MMA makes no attempt to link site logs with individuals that pass through the MMA site. Only authorized MMA staff have access to MMA site information. The MMA does not use cookies on its site. The MMA does not supplement user information with aggregate data. 

**Data Security**  
The security of the information you provide to the MMA is important to us. Registration forms which capture certain information, including credit card transactions, are secured through 128 bit SSL encryption with a registered Verisign SSL certificate. Information is stored in a secure area and only accessible by authorized MMA staff. However, the MMA site includes links to other sites, and when you choose to visit those sites, the MMA cannot assume responsibility for any other site¹s content or information handling practices. We encourage you to review each site¹s privacy policy prior to entering into transactions with the third-party linked sites. 

**Trans-Border Data**  
The MMA is taking reasonable steps to ensure compliance with the U.S. Department of Commerce International "Safe Harbor" Principles, including maintaining adequate privacy protection of transfer of personal data from EU member states. 

**Third-Party Verification**  
To maintain compliance with MMA Privacy Guidelines, the MMA will undergo a privacy audit conducted by an independent third party on a regular basis. The audit opinion and the period to which the opinion covers will be clearly posted on the MMA site. 

**Mobile Marketing Association Contacts**  
We can be reached via e-mail at [](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com)[mma@mmaglobal.com](mailto:mma@mmaglobal.com) with privacy in the subject matter line. 

| 

JOIN THE MMA

NEWSLETTER & ALERTS
